KIRTLEY ADAMS

Columbus, GA 31905 | 317.625.5867 | hello@kirtleymichelle.com

PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

Dedicated and self-motivated Full Stack Web Development Student with experience providing key leadership and direction in client engagement, data management, and complex administrative support. Proven record of collaborating with internal departments and key stakeholders to define business needs. Adept at consolidating information sources to create accurate, detailed reports. Demonstrates strong analytical and problem-solving skills, making competent decisions based on historical data and forecasting. Capable of meeting deadlines and prioritizing assignments to best support goals and objectives. Able to work remotely from a home office environment.

EDUCATION

Bachelor of Business Administration, Minor in Project Management | American Public University Full Stack Web Development Bootcamp | University of Denver

Projected 2023
Projected April 2022

TECHNICAL PROFICIENCIES

Microsoft Office Suite (Word, Excel) | Windows | Asana/Trello | Google Workspace | Canva | Visual Studio | Git | HTML | CSS |

JavaScript | Front- and Back-end Website Design

PROFESSIONAL HISTORY

Stay at Home Mother & Homeschooler | Adams Household - Columbus, GA

2010 - Present

- · Counseled children to help them discover their strengths, how to improve their weaknesses, and to set goals · Utilized varied and engaging multimedia to enhance learning while providing significant improvements to lesson retention · Achieved lesson goals by following procedures and using effective communication skills to convey topics · Increased children's educational and social development by utilizing effective communication skills, including active listening, empathy, and compassion to build trusting relationships
- · Engaged with children in nurturing, safe environments to promote emotional, social, and intellectual growth, regulating schedules to balance rest, learning, and play

Owner & Operator | kirtleymichelle - Columbus, GA

2011 - 2016

- · Managed all aspects of business operations including bookkeeping, marketing, customer service, and inventory management · Prepared and maintained set operational and capital budget goals, managing an approved annual business supply budget and negotiating vendor contracts
- · Leveraged marketing and sales data to identify customers, enhance product promotion, and customer relationship management · Implemented customized sales techniques to successfully sell vehicles and upsell products to customers, increasing profit margins and business growth

VOLUNTEER EXPERIENCE

Executive Assistant | Exceptional Families of the Military

2021 - Present

- · Coordinate with Area Directors, scheduling and distributing monthly emails, assigning tasks or projects to volunteers and Area Directors
- · Support the creation of website content and social media posts, developing brand and content strategies to create cohesive tones across all marketing channels
- · Managing multiple projects, meetings, emails, and information from all Area Directors simultaneously, and ensuring timelines stay on target

- · Coordinate with Area Directors to develop and implement a volunteer onboarding process, scheduling onboarding interviews via web conferencing, distributing monthly volunteer schedulers, and performing exit interviews with outgoing volunteers
- · Support the creation of website content and social media posts, developing brand and content strategies to create cohesive tones across all marketing channels

Girl Scout Cookie Mom | Girl Scouts of the USA

2016 - 2019

· Managed pickup, drop off, and delivery of all cookies for the Troop, tracking payments to ensure 100% order fulfillment

Co-Leader | Soldier & Family Readiness Group (SFRG)

2014 - 2016

· Developed and distributed welcome packets for new members on the military installation, coordinating meetings and group events · Met with installation commanders and leaders every month, providing updates on membership numbers and upcoming events

Treasurer | Soldier & Family Readiness Group (SFRG)

2013 - 2014

- · Managed funds for the US Army SFRG Unit, reconciling account balance sheets, including timely follow up and resolution of outstanding amounts while maintaining relevant supporting documents
- · Prepared and delivered to leadership, under tight turnaround timelines, accurate monthly, quarterly, and annual financial statements

CORE COMPETENCIES

Planning & Organization | Quality Control | Interpersonal Communication | Project Management | System Documentation | Tech Savvy Adaptable & Flexible | Strategic Planning | Schedule Management | Data Entry & Analysis | Database Administration | Problem Solving